## SUMANT BAGRI

#### Masters Student (MScAC) @ University of Toronto

@ sbagri@cs.toronto.edu in sumant-bagri-6aa973100

✓ 65, Marjory Avenue, TorontoØ 0000-0002-7508-905X

Ontario, Canada

## **HIGHLIGHTS**

I am passionate about researching and implementing state-of-the-art deep learning techniques to solve complex, real-world problems in computer vision for robotics and healthcare and that is exactly what I hope to kickstart through this internship and pursue as a career in the future

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Trading Operations Engineer**

#### Flow Traders Asia Pte. Ltd

iii Oct 2020 - Apr 2022

- Hong Kong, Hong Kong
- Manage, maintain and optimize all internal, software and hardware stacks largely integrated with the Linux kernel
- Work with development to build and test exchange APIs for different APAC markets
- Implement automated ops-engines and relevant monitoring tools improving control and enabling streamlined deliveries

## RESEARCH/ACADEMIC PROJECTS

#### Comparison of Sampling-Based Path Planners

**Dec** 2022

UofT, Canada

 Performed a comparative study of three asymptotically optimal, sampling-based path-planners - FMT\*, BIT\* and NRRT\* algorithms. Evaluated optimal path costs, execution times as well as success rates through simulations on characteristically different 2D maps with varying sample counts

## Synthetic Image Generation of Brain Tumor MRI Scans

UofT, Canada

 Implemented three different GAN architectures - DCGAN, WGAN and UNet-GAN - for synthetic image generation using PyTorch.
 Trained a CNN model for brain-tumor classification using synthetic images which achieved 90% accuracy on real images

### Capturing Cutting Tool Failure in Micro-Milling

**Sep 2019 - Aug 2020** 

■ IIT Bombay, India

 Developed an image processing pipeline to extract tool-wear data from captured tool images. Modelled and tuned ANN and DBN to classify and predict tool-wear and end-of-tool-life based on force and vibration data

#### Autonomous Navigation and Obstacle Avoidance Robot

**Oct** 2018

UofT, Canada

 Implemented a depth first search (DFS) path planning algorithm in C++ for self-localization of robot. Enabled optimal collision detection using 8 ultrasonic sensors and implemented PID control for obstacle avoidance

## **EDUCATION**

## MSc, Applied Computing

## University of Toronto, Department of Computer Science

Toronto, Sept 2022 - December 2023\*

<u>Courses</u>: Introduction to Machine Learning, Introduction to Mobile Robotics, Computational Imaging, Visual and Mobile Computing Systems, Neural Networks and Deep Learning

# B.Tech and M.Tech, Mechanical Engineering

#### **IIT Bombay**

india, Aug 2015 - Aug 2020

Minor in Electrical Engineering

## **PUBLICATIONS**

### Journal Articles

Bagri, S., Manwar, A., Varghese, A., Mujumdar, S., & Joshi, S. S. (2021). Tool wear and remaining useful life prediction in micromilling along complex tool paths using neural networks. *Journal of Manufacturing Processes*, 71, 679–698.

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C/C++ Python

Robotics/CV: ROS Gazebo OpenCV

Machine Learning: PyTorch TensorFlow

Cloud Computing: Kubernetes Docker

Distributed Computing: Hadoop Disco

Data Streaming: Kafka ELK Stack

Databases: BigQuery PostgreSQL MariaDB